hello and welcome to how to play
backgammon presented by gather together
games.com
[Music]
this video will cover the basics on how
to play the game backgammon the video
will start with the general concepts and
gameplay and then get into more of the
details for the game backgammon is a
two-player game with a player sitting on
each side of the board the board has
four quadrants and each quadrant has six
points these points can be seen as the
boards spaces giving the board a total
of 24 spaces each player has 15 checkers
player one has the dark colored checkers
and they are set up as follows player 2
has the light colored checkers and they
are set up to mir player ones checkers
during gameplay player ones checkers
will only be able to move
counterclockwise and player twos
checkers will only be able to move
clockwise the object of the game is to
be the first player to remove all his
checkers off the board checkers can be
removed only when all your checkers are
within your home board each players home
board are the first six points in front
of them shown here
for player 1 and here for player 2
the game begins with each player rolling
one die the player with the higher
number rolled gets to use both dice for
the first move player 2 rolled the
higher four and gets to move first the
number rolled on each die equals the
number of spaces the player can move a
checker player 2 moves one checker two
spaces for the two rolled and moves
another checker four spaces for the four
rolled play moves to player one going
forward players rolled their own two
dice and move accordingly player one
rolls a four and A one player 1 moves
one checker four spaces for the four
rolled and moves the same checker one
more space for the one rolled play moves
back to player two to roll players
continue to take turns rolling and
moving checkers a player is not allowed
to move a checker to a space that is
occupied by two or more of the
opponent's checkers here player one
would not be able to move this checker
six spaces for the six rolled since the
landing space is blocked by player two's
checkers when a player lands on a space
that is occupied by only one of the
opponent's checkers the opponent's
checker is moved to the middle bar here
player 1 moves one space for the one
rolled and lands on the single checker
of player two player two's checker is
moved to the middle bar when a player
has a checker on the bar the player must
return it into gameplay before moving
any other checker
a checker on the bar returns to the
board starting with the farthest space
for the player here player 2 will return
the bar to checker one space for the one
rolled now that the checker has been
returned to the board player 2 can move
any checker for the two rolled if a
player rolls the same number on both
dice is known as rolling doubles the
player that rolled doubles gets to move
a total of four times twice for each die
here player 2 rolls double threes a
total of four moves of three spaces each
are taken by player two when moving the
same checker with both dice numbers the
intermediate point has to be open for
example player 1 has rolled a three and
a four
although seven spaces away is open this
move cannot be made because both three
spaces away and four spaces away are
block
going back to the gameplay both players
have moved all their checkers to their
home board once you have all your
checkers in your home board you can
begin taking checkers off the board with
each roll player two rolls and moves a
checker six spaces for these six rolled
to get a checker off the board player
two then moves a checker three spaces
for the three-year-old player one goes
next and can move one checker off the
board with the two rolled and moves one
checker one space for the one rolled
players continue to take turns rolling
and moving the first player with all
their checkers off the board wins a
checker on the bar must be returned into
play before other moves can be made if
the checker is blocked from being
returned into play the players turn is
over with no moves being made if a
higher number is rolled than you have
while bearing off the farthest checker
can be removed
that wraps up how to play backgammon if
you found this video helpful give it a
thumbs up and get more game tutorials by
subscribing to our channel gather
together games thanks for watching
[Music]